Charles Habib Malik Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings, 1930-1994 (Box 231-249)
  - Unidentified
    - Lebanon and the Middle East, circa 1973-1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous topics, undated
    - Philosophical and religious issues, 1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 248)
  - Various notes and fragments, circa 1945-1975, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 249)
- Miscellany, 1888-1982 (Box 249-282)
  Address books, appointment calendars, dissertation, graduate papers and lecture notes, clippings, interviews, biographical information, lists, family papers, notebooks, passports, and photographs.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Academic training (Box 249)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
      - Bibliographies, 1936-1938
      - Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization, 1933-1937 See also Container 183, Immigration and Naturalization Service
      - Ephemera, 1932-1933, undated
      - Lecture notes
        - Carter-Beebe, John Gilbert, 1933
        - Demos, Raphael, 1934
        - Hocking, William Ernest, 1932-1933, (2 folders) (Box 250)
        - Hocking, William Ernest, and Alfred North Whitehead, 1933-1935
        - Lewis, Clarence Irving, 1933-1934, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1933-1934 (Box 251)
        - Sheffer, Henry Maurice, 1932-1933
        - Whitehead, Alfred North, 1932-1933, (3 folders)
        - Woods, James Haughton, 1932
      - Preliminary examination notes and questions, 1933-1937
      - Writings (Box 252)
        - Miscellaneous notes and partial drafts, undated, (2 folders)
        - Student papers
          - 1932-1933, (3 folders)
          - 1934, undated, (2 folders) (Box 253)
        - Thesis (Box 254)
          - Card file, undated
          - Drafts, 1937 (Box 255)
            - Chapters 1-7, (7 folders)
            - Chapters 8-9 and references, (2 folders) (Box 256)
          - Miscellaneous drafts and notes, 1934-1935, undated See also Oversize, (7 folders); (1 folder) (Box 257)
    - Universität Freiburg, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany
      - Lecture notes
        - Bröcker, Walter, 1935
        - Heidegger, Martin, 1935-1936, (2 folders)
        - Honecker, Martin, 1936
      - Miscellany, 1935-1936
  - Address books
    - 1934, 1945-1950, (3 folders)
    - Undated, (5 folders) (Box 258)
  - Appointment calendars
    - 1923-1929, (6 folders)
    - 1932-1945, (11 folders) (Box 259)
    - 1946-1948, (5 folders) (Box 260)
    - 1949-1951, (6 folders) (Box 261)
    - 1952-1955, (4 folders) (Box 262)
    - 1956-1958, (6 folders) (Box 263)
    - 1959-1965, (7 folders) (Box 264)
    - 1965-1978, 1981, (7 folders) (Box 265)
  - Bibliographies
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-1939, undated
    - Personal library
      - Annotated lists, 1945, 1976, undated
      - Card file, undated (Box 266)
    - Publications and speeches by Malik (Box 267)
      - Card file, undated
      - Card file, undated, (2 folders) (Box 268)
      - Lists, 1965, undated
  - Biographical information, 1935-1975, undated
  - Certificates, 1947-1957, undated See Oversize
  - Christmas card, mailing, and guest lists, 1946-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 269)
  - Clippings
    - 1945-1949, (5 folders)
    - 1950-1954, (5 folders) (Box 270)
    - 1955-1957, (6 folders) (Box 271)
    - 1957-1958, (7 folders) (Box 272)
    - 1958-1960, (5 folders) (Box 273)
    - 1961-1965, (5 folders) (Box 274)
    - 1965-1969, (4 folders) (Box 275)
    - 1970-1974, (4 folders) (Box 276)
    - 1975-1981, undated, (6 folders) (Box 277)
  - Family papers (Box 278)
    - Malik, Eva Badr (wife), and the Badr family, 1914-1963, undated, (2 folders)
    - Malik, Habib Khalil (father)
      - Diaries, notebooks, and patient logbooks
        - 1888-1914, (4 folders)
        - 1908-1916, (4 folders) (Box 279)
        - 1914-1919, 1934, undated, (4 folders) (Box 280)
      - Miscellany, 1919-1942, undated
    - Malik, Habib C. (son), 1958-1982, undated
    - Melick, Aziz Bey, 1934
  - Home, Rabiya, Lebanon, 1963-1971 (Box 281)
  - Interviews
    - 1945-1978, (5 folders)
    - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 282)
  - List of files, undated
  - Notebooks, 1923, circa 1944-1957, undated, (7 folders)
  - Passports, 1945-1955
  - Photographs, undated See Oversize
- Oversize, 1937-1976 (Box OV 1)
  Certificates, telex messages, research notes, posters, and photographs.
  Organized and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - United Nations (Box OV 1)
    - United Nations Day, 1950 (Container 98)
  - Subject File
    - Front of Freedom and Man in Lebanon, 1976, undated (Containers 145-146)
  - Miscellany
    - Academic training
      - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
        - Thesis
          - Miscellaneous drafts and notes, 1935 (Container 256)
    - Certificates, 1947-1957, undated (Container 268)
    - Photographs, undated (Container 282)
- Closed (Box X 1)
  Book-length manuscript. Described according to the series and container which it was removed.
  - Writings (Box X 1)
    - Books
      - [Title withheld] (Container 243), (3 folders)
- Classified, 1949-1959 (Box CL 1)
  Correspondence, memoranda, cable, resolutions, and reports.
  - United Nations (Box CL 1)
    - Topical file
      - Soviet peace resolution, 1949 (Container 95)
  - Subject File
    - Asian-African Conference, Bandung, Indonesia
      - Statements and background reports, undated (Container 130)
    - China lobby, 1951 (Container 137)
    - Communism, undated (Container 140)
    - United States government
      - American embassy, Beirut, Lebanon, 1957-1958 (Container 182)